

Hi, I'm Neil.

I love to solve problems with obvious designs and minimal code.

I'm a UX designer & software developer who is obsessed with making great products. I've been designing and building websites for over 13 years. I'm a generalist who can take a project from ideation to final product. Here's what I've been up to lately:

EXPERIENCE



Tabule

Founder 2012 - Present

Built web and iOS apps for importing syllabi, managing homework, and collaborating with classmates. Developed advanced technologies, like a natural language processing library and clustering algorithms for analyzing student workload. Secured funding for the company and grew to thousands of college students across hundreds of schools. App is loved by students and highly rated.



Eligo Energy

Developer 2013 - Present

Design and build tools for brokers to sell energy to large commercial clients and internal tools to automate expensive manual operations. Learned tech stack within one week of joining the company, and was solely responsible for multiple internal projects soon after.



Undesigned

Partner Present

Consult with Chicago startups to help them affordably develop usable designs and working prototypes. Also help startups create sustainable business models, appropriate branding strategies, and more.



PepsiCo

All-Stars Consultant 2012

Helped develop strategies for a new nutrition product for PepsiCo, responsible for presenting creative initiatives, such as brand and design, channels and adoption, and feedback and fluctuation, working both individually and collaboratively.

SKILLS

DESIGN

User Flows

Wireframes Storyboards

UX Testing

Prototyping

Visual Design

Business Design

TECH

Rubu

Ruby on Rails

JavaScript

jQuery

Titanium

Regex

SQL

Java EE

PHP

Objective-C

Python

HTML/CSS



Illinois Institute of Technology

Teaching Assistant for Computer Science 2012

Taught students basics of programming and algorithms, as well as graded labs and provided office hours.



Haiti Ministry of Education / OLPC

Tech Team Lead 2011

Worked with team to design cost-effective system for powering OLPC laptops in Haitian schools with solar energy, and setup a low-power local server for students to access Wikipedia without an internet connection.



Alzheimer's Association

Technical Assistant 2009 - 2010

Contacted professors and medical experts around the world to participate in the Association's internal review program, held fastest typing record among interns.



Athleague (Acquired by IMLeagues)

UI Engineer 2007

Designed, prototyped, and implemented all of the front-end and significant portions of the back-end of the web app. Rapidly developed and deployed a successful application from start to finish with limited time and resources.

EDUCATION



Illinois Institute of Technology

B.S., Computer Science & Psychology, minor in Entrepreneurship 2008 - 2012

Graduated cum laude, recipient of IIT University Scholarship, Heald Scholarship, Kern Innovation and Entrepreneurship Academy Scholarship, and Chicago Mayor's ThinkChicago Fellow. President of Entrepreneurship club.



Now that you have a small taste of who I am, ready to make awesome products together?

Learn more



Get in touch

Read my blog at metamorphium.com
Check out my code at github.com/neilgupta
See my designs at dribbble.com/neilgupta
Follow me at twitter.com/neilgupta

neil@metamorphium.com 408-931-2392 600 S Dearborn St #1105 Chicago, IL 60605

FUN FACTS

My favorite city is Paris after studying abroad there in 2010.

I love strategy board games and want to play all top 100 games on BGG. I'm only 9% done.

I grew up in San Jose, CA, but currently enjoy freezing in Chicago.

I love Mexican food, but I hate cilantro.

I prefer new experiences over repeating the same thing.

I'm a workaholic who doesn't drink caffeine.

I'm an introvert who enjoys working with others.